Rush family papers LCP.Rush
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series II. James Rush papers
  - Subseries IV. Correspondence, circa 1813-1869
    - C. Dr. James and Mrs. Phoebe Rush's invitations, acceptances and rejections of social events, [Yi2 7407 -Yi2 7413]
      - Smith, Uselma C. regarding the death of Mrs. Eliza Jones, 1863 March 5 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Sperry, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Spruill, S.H., 1858 September 6 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Starr, J. Leander, 1858, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Staunton, Sir George, 1845 June-July (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Stevens, Pariset Guion [invitation to the funeral of], 1842 August 16 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Stewart, William [invitation to the funeral of], 1837 April 11 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Stiles, Edward James [invitation to the funeral of], 1850 August 26 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Stocker, Mrs. and Miss, 1836, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Sullivan, J.T.S., 1840-1844, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Survilliers, Comte de, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Swift, J., undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Sykes, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Taggart, Miss, 1838 February 3 (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - Tawse, Mr. and Mrs., 1810 July 21 (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Taylor, F. (address wrapper only), undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Taylor, G.M., undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Taylor, Mrs., undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Thibaud, Mr. and Miss, 1838 December 25 (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - Thomson, Dr., 1869 December 20 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Thomson, C. Rockland, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Thomson, Misses, undated (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Thomson, G.H., undated (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - Thomson, John D., undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - Thouron, Mr. A., undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Tiers, H.C., undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
      - Tiers, Sally J., undated (Box 11, Folder 43)
      - Tilghman, Mr. and Mrs. B., undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
      - Tilghman, M., undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
      - Trudeau, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
      - Tucker, Dr., undated (Box 11, Folder 47)
      - Tunis, Mrs., undated (Box 11, Folder 48)
      - Turner, Miss, undated (Box 11, Folder 49)
      - Turner, Abby Ann [invitation to the funeral of], undated (Box 11, Folder 50)
      - Twells, Mr., undated (Box 11, Folder 51)
      - Tyson, J.R., undated (Box 11, Folder 52)
      - United Bowmen, 1938-1939 (Box 11, Folder 53)
      - Vallette, Mrs. Mary, undated (Box 11, Folder 54)
      - Valville, Mr de, undated (Box 11, Folder 55)
      - Vandenhoff, L.E., undated (Box 11, Folder 56)
      - Vandenhoff, J., undated (Box 11, Folder 57)
      - Van Pelt, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 11, Folder 58)
      - Van Pelt, Peter [invitation to the funeral of], 1834 May 14 (Box 11, Folder 59)
      - Vere, Lady Elizabeth Hope, undated (Box 11, Folder 60)
      - Waddell, F.S. (verses), undated (Box 11, Folder 61)
      - Wadsworth, Mr. and Miss, undated (Box 11, Folder 62)
      - Wallace, Mr. and Mrs. J.W. and Misses, undated (Box 11, Folder 63)
      - Wallington, Mrs. Catherine [invitation to the funeral of], 1839 October 30 (Box 11, Folder 64)
      - Walmsley, Mr., undated (Box 11, Folder 65)
      - Waln, Mr., undated (Box 11, Folder 66)
      - Waln, William, undated (Box 11, Folder 67)
      - Walsh, Mr. and Miss, 1843, undated (Box 11, Folder 68)
      - Warley, Miss, undated (Box 11, Folder 69)
      - Watmough, Colonel, Mrs. and Miss, undated (Box 11, Folder 70)
      - Watmough, Mrs. J.G., undated (Box 11, Folder 71)
      - Watson, Mr., undated (Box 11, Folder 72)
      - Wells, Mr. and Miss, undated (Box 11, Folder 73)
      - West, Dr., undated (Box 11, Folder 74)
      - Westminster, Lady, undated (Box 11, Folder 75)
      - Wetherill, Elisha K. [invitation to the funeral of], 1836 June 25 (Box 11, Folder 76)
      - Wharton, Misses, undated (Box 11, Folder 77)
      - Wharton, Charles, undated (Box 11, Folder 78)
      - Wharton, Francis, undated (Box 11, Folder 79)
      - Wharton, F.R., undated (Box 11, Folder 80)
      - Wharton, G.M., undated (Box 11, Folder 81)
      - Wharton, T.F., undated (Box 11, Folder 82)
      - White, William, undated (Box 11, Folder 83)
      - White, Mr. and Miss, undated (Box 11, Folder 84)
      - Wilcocks, Mr. and Misses, undated (Box 11, Folder 85)
      - Williams, H.J., undated (Box 11, Folder 86)
      - Williams, J.R., undated (Box 11, Folder 87)
      - Williams, J.W., undated (Box 11, Folder 88)
      - Willig, Miss, undated (Box 11, Folder 89)
      - Willing, Mr., undated (Box 11, Folder 90)
      - Willing, Dr., undated (Box 11, Folder 91)
      - Willing, Mrs. and Miss, and Miss Sperry, undated (Box 11, Folder 92)
      - Willing, Edward S., undated (Box 11, Folder 93)
      - Willing, Ellen, undated (Box 11, Folder 94)
      - Willing, [D.]F., undated (Box 11, Folder 95)
      - Willing, Mrs. G., undated (Box 11, Folder 96)
      - Willing, Mrs. R., undated (Box 11, Folder 97)
      - Wilmer, Mrs., undated (Box 11, Folder 98)
      - Wilson, Mr., undated (Box 11, Folder 99)
      - Wood, Dr., undated (Box 11, Folder 100)
      - Wood, Mr. G., undated (Box 11, Folder 101)
      - Woodforde, Anna Julia [invitation to the funeral of], 1838 November 1 (Box 11, Folder 102)
      - Wray, Mrs. Ann [invitation to the funeral of], 1835 March 4 (Box 11, Folder 103)
      - Young, Mr., undated (Box 11, Folder 104)
      - Young, T.H., undated (Box 11, Folder 105)
      - Zetland, Lord and Lady, undated (Box 11, Folder 106)
      - Calling cards A-Q, undated (Box 12)
      - Calling cards R-Y, invitations, tickets to events, lecture announcements, notes, and advertising cards, undated (Box 13)
  - Subseries V. Medical Practice
    - Record of Deaths of Patients of James Rush, 1813 (Volume 365)
    - Practical Register (includes monthly weather descriptions, observations on diseases, and a check list of body parts affected), 1813-1818, 1838-1840 (Volume 366)
    - Nosological or Observative Medicine, 1835-1838 (Volume 367)
    - James Rush's dispute with the College of Physicians of Philadelphia regarding their refusal to back their own fee schedule, 1841 (Volume 368)
    - Medical Notes, undated; [Yi2 7266] (Volume 369)
    - St. George's Hospital Cases, etc., undated (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Subseries VI. Students and Lectures
    - Lecture notes taken by James Rush, 1809; [Yi2 7406 43] (Volume 370)
    - Present Pupils of James Rush (a list of pupils who attended the five courses of lectures read from the manuscripts of Dr. Benjamin Rush), 1813-1819 (Volume 371)
    - Introductory lecture, by James Rush, 1813-1814 (Volume 372)
    - Introductory lecture, by James Rush, 1815 (Volume 373)
    - Introductory lecture, by James Rush, 1817 (Volume 374)
    - Introductory lecture, by James Rush, 1818 (Volume 375)
    - Lecture: "Asiastic Spasmodic Cholera", 1832 (Volume 376)
    - Lecture: "Materia Medica", undated (Volume 377)
  - Subseries VII. Financial Records
    - House on Chestnut Street, Accounts, etc., 1848-1849 (Volume 378)
    - Financial and other memoranda regarding groceries, recipes, menus and balls (includes loose sheets), 1853-1855 (Volume 379)
    - Marketting accounts, 1857-1867 (Volume 380-389)
    - Catalogue of the Private Library of the late James Rush, M.D., bequeathed to the Ridgway Branch of the Philadelphia Library, 1869 (Volume 390)
- Series III. Other Rush family papers
  - Subseries I. Judge Jacob Rush papers
    - Charges to the Grand Jury, 1792-1803 (Volume 391-399)
  - Subseries II. John Rush
    - John Rush letters and land papers (from John Rush to his father Benjamin Rush, plus other documents), 1788-1815 (Volume 32, Pages 1-61)
    - Diploma from the University of Pennsylvania, 1804 June 6 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Subseries III. Richard Rush
    - Letters of Richard Rush, 1801-1849 (Volume 44, Pages 1-122)
    - Letterbook of Richard Rush, Attorney General of Pennsylvania, 1811 (Volume 400)
    - Manuscript of Residence at the Court of London (contains recollections of official and personal activities during 1817-1819, Rush's first year as United States Minister to Great Britain), 1833 (Volume 401)
  - Subseries IV. William Rush
    - Letters to Julia Rush from William Rush, 1823, 1826 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Letter to Julia Rush from William Rush and Elizabeth Fox Rush, 1829 August 4 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Julia Rush from William Rush, 1830-1831 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Letter to Julia Rush from William Rush, 1832 August 30 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Examinations on Materia Medica in the Philadelphia School of Medicine, by William Rush, MD, 1832 (Volume 402)
  - Subseries V. Correspondence, diaries, genealogies and diplomas
    - Music composition book presented to Mrs. Ann Rush by Frank Johnson, 1820 (Volume 403)
    - Letter to Ann Rush from unknown writer, 1836, February 9 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Letter to Anna Rush from F. Mancinelli, 1839, August 31 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Letter to Dr. Benjamin Rush, Jr. from Mary V. Morse, 1867 January 25 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Elizabeth Rush from J.E. Washington, 1834 July 10 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Jacob Rush's diploma from Princeton University, 1805 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Letters to the Library Company of Philadelphia/regarding the Library Company of Philadelphia from James Rush, 1843-1848 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Letter to Phoebe Ann Rush from Anna Maria Rush, thanking her for a dress, 1843 November 30 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Letter to unknown recipient from Thomas Stritch, 1806 November 10 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Letter to unknown recipient from Samuel Moore, 1840 June 23 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Letter to unknown recipient from unknown author, 1862 January 24 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Letter to unknown recipient from J.R. Stout, 1866 January 25 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Letter to unknown recipient from Georgina Clark, 1866 October 13 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Letter to unknown recipient from M.A. and M.C. Peale, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Ridgeway genealogy (six accounts), 1855-1894 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Financial ledger and Ridgeway genealogy, circa 1867 (Volume 404)
    - Newspapers with genealogical information on Egg Harbor families, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Diary of Cassie Murray Rush (includes descriptions of her visits to the Centennial), 1876 (Volume 405)
    - Unattributed diary, 1863 (Volume 406)
    - Unattributed notebook, 1830-1836 (Volume 407)
- Series IV. Miscellaneous documents
  - Poem by unknown author, 1805 November 10 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Gregory's lecture ticket, 1809 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Manuscript of article regarding petroleum, 1812 July 31 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - "On Solitude" by Zimmerman, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Wheatley, Phyllis: manuscript poems on "America, "Box," "Atheism," and "To the Honorable Commodore Hood", undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Size of G. Colburn's head, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Endorsements, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Extracts from letters of pleasantry, undated (Box 14, Folder 30)